tri-c.edu 2019-07-09

# Privacy Policy

### Purpose

Cuyahoga Community College (“College”) websites were created to provide information to the general public about the College and provide online services to students, faculty and staff. Online services include, but are not limited to, admissions, class registration, tuition payment and financial aid and class schedules. The College recognizes the importance of protecting the privacy rights of the users. All personally identifiable information shared on the College’s online service website is securely managed and safeguarded in accordance with the policies and guidelines set forth below.

### Policy Applicability

The Web Privacy Policy applies generally to the information collected by or submitted to official College websites. However, the amount and type of information collected may vary from site to site and by web page controls.

The College gathers certain types of information provided by the user to help better serve their needs. The College wants the user to fully understand the terms and conditions surrounding the gathering and use of information. This privacy policy discloses what information we gather and how we use it. The College will not sell, exchange or otherwise distribute this information without the user’s consent except when required by law.

### 1.0 Policy

**1.1 Site Definitions**

The College’s web space includes numerous sites with varying levels of connections to the College as outlined below.

**1.2 Official College Websites**

Except as noted, the information in this privacy policy applies to all official College websites, defined as the web pages of the College and its departments, divisions or other units and any other sites specifically designated as official by the College.

**1.3 Unofficial Websites**

Within the College’s domain, signified by the address "tri-c.edu" or the range of Internet protocol addresses assigned to the College, a user may find websites over which the College has no control. Such sites are considered unofficial and include, but are not limited to, the web pages of individual faculty members or students as well as the web pages of student organizations and other entities that are not formally part of the College.

The College encourages compliance with the privacy statements of each respective site.

**1.4 Third Party Websites**

The College may provide links to other websites of interest to provide services for its users. The College is not responsible for the content and privacy practices of these websites. The use of such linked sites is subject to the privacy statements and use requirements of each respective site; please check each site for its respective privacy policy.

**1.5 Social Media, Social/Ad Retargeting & Pixels**

The College’s online and mobile communications may contain links and pixels directed to other websites and social media platforms. Some links and pixels may retarget to College-sponsored content such as the Tri-C Jazz Fest.  Other links and pixels may redirect to websites or platforms such as Facebook, Twitter, or Pinterest, etc. The College is not responsible for the privacy practices, policies, or content of any of these websites or platforms. This Privacy Policy does not apply to any outside websites or platforms. The College has no control over the collection or use of Information, including personal information, on any external websites or platforms.

**1.6 Policy Applicability**

The Web Privacy Policy applies generally to the information collected by or submitted to official College websites. However, the amount and type of information collected may vary from site to site and web page unit controls.

### 2.0 Information College Gathers

When website users access official “tri-c.edu” web pages, certain essential and nonessential technical information (collectively referred to as access information) is automatically collected. No other information is collected through our official websites except when deliberate information is sent to the College (ex., by sending the College an e-mail or providing requested information on a service website). Examples of the information a website user might choose to send the College is listed below as "optional information" (see section 2.1.2).

**2.1 Access Information (automatically collected)  **

The following types of information are automatically collected whenever a user accesses a page on the College’s website.

Client information: user's authentication information and Internet address. 

Essential technical information: identification of the page or service a user is requesting; type of browser and operating system a user is using; and the date and time of access. 

Nonessential technical information: non-personally-identifiable aggregated tracking information derived mainly by tallying page views throughout our sites.

**2.2 Optional information (deliberately sent)**  

The College also collects information that is submitted by website users. This includes but is not limited to: 

E-mail: user’s name, e-mail address. 

Online forms: all information/data user provides or confirms.

**2.3 Cookies**

The College sometimes transfers “cookies” and “applets” to the user’s hard drive through the user’s web browser. Cookies are identifiers that are used to identify a computer, store user preferences and settings, help with sign-in and analyze site operations.

Important things to know about our tracking cookies:

  * No personal information is collected through these cookies. 
  * All tracking data collected through these cookies is viewable in aggregate form only and does not disclose any personal information. 
  * A cookie can't read data off the user’s hard drive or read cookie files created by other sites.

### 3.0 Use of Information

The College uses the obtained information to determine which sites visitors like and don't like based on traffic to those sites. The College does not track what individual visitors read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps the College provide the best services to its users.

The College tracks search terms entered in the search function, but it does not track which terms a particular user enters. Optional information submitted through forms may be used to provide assistance and services to website users. E-mail addresses may be used to contact individuals concerning questions or for the delivery of newsletters and other informative publications as compliant with the CAN-SPAM Act of 2003.

**3.1 Sharing of Information**

The College does not divulge any information about an individual website user to a third party except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public. Users should be aware that some information collected from the College’s  websites may be subject to the Ohio Public Records Act (O.R.C § 149.43).This means that while the College does not actively share information, in some cases it may be compelled by law to release information gathered from one of its sites.

**3.2 Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974**

The College complies with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA), as amended, which provides students the right to access a copy of their student records; permits students with the right to contest incorrect information in their student records; and limits the release of such information without students’ explicit written consent. Student "directory information" may be released without the student's written consent.

Information regarding Student Education Records and FERPA is available by [clicking here [DH1]](https://web.archive.org/web/20190709184237id_/https%3A//www.tri-c.edu/administrative-departments/office-of-legal-services/student-education-records-and-ferpa.html). Questions regarding Student Education Records or FERPA should be directed to the Legal Services department at legal@tri-c.edu or 216-987-4856.

**3.3 Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA)**

Certain optional information submitted by users may be considered Protected Health Information (PHI). The College complies with the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA), which regulates the use and disclosure of PHI.

**3.4 Users from Outside the United States**

The College’s website is provided and operated from within the United States and is subject to the applicable state and federal laws of the United States. Use of website user information by the College is intended for use only within the United States and its territories.  If you are located outside the United States, please be aware that your information is being transferred to and stored in the United States.  Use of this site outside of the United States is at your own risk, and you agree to comply with all applicable laws and use or nonuse of content.

### 4.0 Procedures and Responsibilities

**4.1 Security**

The College strives to protect the security of the information provided by its users; however, such security measures cannot be guaranteed. The College operates secure data networks protected by industry standard and best practice. Passwords are required to access personally identifiable information including, but not limited to, contact information, class records and tuition-payment history. This information is accessible only to the individual the record pertains to and authorized College faculty and staff. The security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary. The College does not guarantee the security of the information transmitted, and users utilize the site at their own risk.

**4.2 Changes to the policy**

Changes in the law, in technology, and the College’s attempts to serve its users may cause this policy to be changed from time to time and without further notice. The user’s continued use of the site after any such changes constitutes their acceptance of the new terms. If the user does not agree with the new terms or any future terms, the user should not use the site. The College will use reasonable efforts to communicate any changes to this policy.
